<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Policies>
	<Policy-Summary number="11">
		<Header>
			User Account Hardening
		</Header>
		<Base-Text>
			These policies prevent security issues that lead to the exploitation of your sensitive data in AD Computers.
		</Base-Text>
		<Vuln>
			Follow the guidance to protect your computer from these vulnerabilities.
		</Vuln>
		<Not-Vuln></Not-Vuln>
		<Vulnerabilities>
			<Vulnerability position="0"></Vulnerability>
			<Vulnerability position="1"></Vulnerability>
			<Vulnerability position="4"></Vulnerability>
		</Vulnerabilities>
		<Policies>
			<Policy name="Require domain users to elevate when setting a network's location" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This policy locates at "Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Network > Network Connections > Require domain users to elevate when setting a network’s location."
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This policy is disabled. In general, this is less secure for data, and this policy should be enabled. See guidance for a more in-depth explanation.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This policy is enabled. In general, this is the more secure option for data. There is a more in-depth explanation of why and why not to enable this in the guidance.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This policy has not been configured and defaults to disabled. In general, this is less secure for data, and this policy should be enabled. See guidance for a more in-depth explanation.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Do not display the password reveal button" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This policy locates at "Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Credential User Interface > Do not display the password reveal button."
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, allowing users to show their password on their screen in plain text where it can be seen and used by anyone nearby. It is recommended to enable this policy.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, so users cannot show their password field in plain text, which is the more secure option.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting has not been configured and, by default, is disabled, allowing users to show their password on their screen in plain text where it can be seen and used by anyone nearby. It is recommended to enable this policy.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Prevent the usage of OneDrive for file storage" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This policy locates at "Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > OneDrive > Prevent the usage of OneDrive for file storage."
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is enabled, allowing OneDrive ruuning on Windows 10. This increases vulnerabilities and allows easier access with stolen credentials. This setting should be enabled.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, meaning that OneDrive is completely disallowed.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						The OneDrive default setting allows OneDrive to be running, increasing vulnerabilities from attacking.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Do not sync" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This policy locates at "Computer Configuration > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Sync your settings > Do not sync."
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so if a file-sharing system is used, it will always be up to date, regardless of the data sensitivity, giving an attacker easier access to it.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, meaning that even if a file-sharing system (not recommended) is used, data from users will not necessarily be stored there, allowing them to only store necessary data there and to avoid leaving sensitive data in an easier-to-attack-location.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured and, by default, disabled, so if a file-sharing system is used, it will always be up to date, regardless of the data sensitivity, giving an attacker easier access to it.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Allow Cortana" default="2" recommended="0">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under "Computer Configuration > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Search > Allow Cortana."
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, and it is recommended to keep it this way.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, which is not the recommended state, as it opens up potential vulnerabilities in Cortana. It is recommended to disable.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured. If you are not on Windows 10, this setting can be safely ignored. If you are, it is strongly recommended to explicitly disable this due to potential vulnerabilities.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Don't search the web or display web results in Search" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Search > Don’t search the web or display web results in the search.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This disabled setting means web searching in addition to system, decreasing the effectiveness of local searching. Enable this policy is recommended.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						The setting is enabled. Your devices are not in risk because of the additional Internet searching.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured. If you've on Windows 10 in your domain, it's recommend to disable this policy.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			
			<Policy name="Turn off the Store application" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under "Computer Configuration > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Store > Turn off the Store application"
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, allowing download risked application from Store. It is recommended to enable this setting.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, so users cannot use Store to update applications. Recommend using 'winget' instead.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, allowing insecure use of Store (e.g. downloading unverified malware) onto Windows devices. Enabling this policy is recommended.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Screen saver timeout" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under User Configuration > Administrative Templates > Control Panel > Personalization > Screen saver timeout.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, allowing users leaving their device with no locking threshold. It's recommended to enabled this policy and time limit is 10m.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled. The recommended value is 10m.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This policy is not configured. By default, the screen saver time is 15m.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Turn off picture password sign-in" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Administrative Templates > System > Logon > Turn off picture password sign-in
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, disallowing users from activating picture passwords and making their accounts more secure as a result.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			
			<Policy name="Use a hardware security device" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Windows Hello for Business > Use a hardware security device.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled. This allows attack from inserting special keys into your Windows kernel. Enabling this policy is recommended.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This policy is enabled.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This policy is not configured, which means the TPM is not required to use Windows Hello for Bussiness. Enabling this policy is recommended.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			
			<Policy name="Summary" default="0" recommended="0" recommendedColour="Black">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Generally, these policies maximize securiy at the cost of reducing user experience. Most of services are unlikely to be needed for users.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
		</Policies>
	</Policy-Summary>
	<Policy-Summary number="10">
		<Header>
			User Authentication
		</Header>
		<Base-Text>
			These policies generally deal with device accessible. If Remote Access or special AD accessible is enabled, bad policy configurations will put your AD under the risk.
		</Base-Text>
		<Vuln>
			Currently, there are vulnerabilities with your user authentication policies. Follow the guidance in the following pages to secure yourself against these vulnerabilities.
		</Vuln>
		<Not-Vuln>
			Currently, there are no detected vulnerabilities with your user authentication policies. The search is not guaranteed to be exhaustive, so some vulnerabilities may still exist, just not the most serious ones that are currently known. You can skip them safety.
		</Not-Vuln>
		<Vulnerabilities>
			<Vulnerability position="2">
				Users can currently set short passwords. It's recommended to set longer passwords.
			</Vulnerability>
			<Vulnerability position="4">
				Complex password is not required. This will put the leaks of passwords, allowing attacker from stoling your data.
			</Vulnerability>
			<Vulnerability position="7">
				Your lockout policy is unsafe. It's recommended to recheck your security policies.
			</Vulnerability>
		</Vulnerabilities>
		<Policies>
			<!--Authentication policy-->
			<Policy name="MinimumPasswordAge" default="0" recommended="2">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Account Policies > Password Policy > Minimum password age.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Your minimum password age is 0. This allows users to cycle through passwords to return to a previous password so they can continue using an old insecure password. Consider changing this value to 1 so users must create new passwords.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="6-999">
						Your minimum password age is %NUM% days. This prevents users from changing their passwords very often. Consider shortening this time (But keeping it above 0) for added security
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-5">
						Your minimum password age is %NUM% days. This will allow users to change passwords frequently without cycling to reuse old passwords often enough to be insecure.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="MaximumPasswordAge" default="0" recommended="2">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Account Policies > Password Policy > Maximum password age.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-20">
						Your maximum password age is %NUM% days. This means your users will have to change their password too frequently and will encourage them to use insecure easy-to-guess passwords and/or store them in easy-to-access areas. Consider increasing this value.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="150-999">
						Your maximum password age is %NUM% days. This allows your users to keep passwords for a very long time, increasing the chances they will be compromised and used before being changed. Consider decreasing this value.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="21-149">
						Your maximum password age is %NUM% days. This should make your users change their password frequently enough without frustrating them and encouraging them to be insecure.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="MinimumPasswordLength" default="0" recommended="2">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Account Policies > Password Policy > Minimum password length.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						You do not require your users to have passwords. This is incredibly unsafe and allows potential attackers easy access to your systems and data.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-9">
						Your minimum password length is %NUM%. This is quite a short password for your users, and while it offers some security, it could be quite easily cracked by a determined attacker. Consider making this value higher to force your users to have longer, harder-to-crack passwords.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="10-14">
						Your minimum password length is %NUM%. While this is a long enough password to be hard to crack, you should still make sure your other password policies are strong enough as well.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="PasswordHistorySize" default="24" recommended="2">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Account Policies > Password Policy > Enforce password history.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						You allow your users to reuse passwords as often as they like. Many users will opt to reuse the same password repeatedly, meaning if they are compromised, there will be a way into your system for a very long time.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-5">
						You remember %NUM% passwords. While this does force users to change passwords, there are few enough that simple variations can be used. A longer history would help to force users to make different passwords.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="6-24">
						You remember %NUM% passwords. Users will likely have to come up with new passwords; however, this will only be effective in conjunction with a long enough minimum password age.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="PasswordComplexity" default="1" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Account Policies > Password Policy > Password must meet complexity requirements.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Your password complexity settings are disabled. This allows users to create incredibly simple passwords that can be easily guessed or cracked.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Your password complexity settings are enabled. This makes sure users cannot create passwords that are too simple. Ensure other settings are similarly secure for strong and secure passwords that protect your system.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="ClearTextPassword" default="0" recommended="0">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Account Policies > Password Policy > Store passwords using reversible encryption.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Reversible encryption storage is disabled. This means the passwords are stored with irreversible encryption, and so is the more secure option.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Reversible encryption storage is enabled. This is the less secure option and is hardly more secure than storing in plain text. Any breach will leak usable passwords. Unless this is a necessary feature, consider disabling this for security.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Summary" default="0" recommended="0" recommendedColour="Black">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Unfortunately, user-generated passwords are inherently weak against targeted attacks, and word lists are used to narrow down the likely phrases along with rules to predict how users will use special characters, capital letters, and numbers, which greatly narrows down the expected possibilities to check.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="LockoutBadCount" default="0" recommended="3">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Account Policies > Account Lockout Policy > Account lockout threshold.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						There is currently no lockout policy. This means attackers can make essentially unlimited attempts to log in, giving them a good chance to find at least one valid password. Consider enabling lockout to prevent this.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-3">
						You allow %NUM% attempts at getting the correct password. Typos are not uncommon, and you will see a large number of users being locked out, which in addition to lowering productivity, will encourage users to use easier passwords. Assuming the password policy is secure, you can allow more attempts without compromising security.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="15-999">
						You allow %NUM% attempts at getting the correct password. This is a lot of attempts and far more than any user should need. Attackers will benefit by being able to try quite a large number of common passwords, especially if you don't have a strong password policy. Consider reducing the number of allowed attempts
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="4-14">
						You allow %NUM% attempts at getting the correct password. This should give plenty of attempts for the user without giving any serious security concerns. However, make sure your password policy is strong so that attackers can't easily guess some passwords in these few attempts.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="LockoutDuration" default="0" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Account Policies > Account Lockout Policy > Account lockout duration.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						There is no lockout policy, so there is also no lockout duration.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-60">
						Your lockout duration is %NUM% minutes. While this gives multiple attempts to an attacker, for instance, overnight, with few enough attempts given per lockout, this is not a problem.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="61-99999">
						Your lockout duration is %NUM% minutes. This will keep attackers from making too many attempts at any given time; however, if an administrator is not easy to access, this could leave users locked out of their accounts for a very long time.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="ResetLockoutCount" default="0" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Account Policies > Account Lockout Policy > Reset account lockout counter after.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						There is no lockout policy, so there is also no reset interval.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-60">
						Your lockout counter reset time is %NUM% minutes. This setting is only an issue if many attempts are given per lockout or if this is far longer than the lockout setting. While this value should not be visible or known to an attacker if figured out, that could be used to circumvent a longer lockout time. Make sure this value is not too different from the lockout duration.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="61-99999">
						Your lockout counter reset time is %NUM% minutes. This, in particular, is not an issue; however, it means your lockout duration is potentially long enough to keep a user locked out for too long. In addition, make sure this value is not too different from the lockout duration; otherwise, it can be used to circumvent the lockout time if figured out.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
		</Policies>
	</Policy-Summary>
	<Policy-Summary number="11">
		<Header>
			System Hardening
		</Header>
		<Base-Text>
			These policies deal with connections to and from the user's device and how easy it will be to connect devices, both physically and through the network. In addition, this also controls how much data is sent to Windows for diagnostics
		</Base-Text>
		<Vuln>
			Currently, there are vulnerabilities in your system security. Follow the guidance in the following pages to secure yourself against these vulnerabilities.
		</Vuln>
		<Not-Vuln>
			Currently, there are no detected vulnerabilities with your system security. The search is not guaranteed to be exhaustive, so some vulnerabilities may still exist, just not the most serious ones that are currently known. While it is recommended to look at the policies you have set to understand why they are important, you can skip this section below.
		</Not-Vuln>
		<Vulnerabilities>
			<Vulnerability position="3">
				Your users may currently be vulnerable to several known hardware exploits that use very simple-looking media. Also, certain apple devices may be vulnerable to 2-way complete access - where a plugged-in media can access all files on the main device.
			</Vulnerability>
			<Vulnerability position="4">
				Windows do not automatically update, so given how infrequently an average user will attempt to update, this could leave vulnerabilities that have been found and patched open for exploitation on user devices for a long time.
			</Vulnerability>
		</Vulnerabilities>
		<Policies>
			<Policy name="Allow Telemetry" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Data Collection and Preview Builds > Allow Telemetry.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so users can set their own telemetry settings. In general, it is slightly more secure to disable it by setting it to 0 - Security or 1 - Basic if not on Windows Enterprise.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, so users cannot set their own telemetry settings. Ensure this is set to 0 - Secure if on Windows Enterprise, or 1 - Basic otherwise.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, so users can set their own telemetry settings. In general, it is slightly more secure to disable it by setting it to 0 - Security or 1 - Basic if not on Windows Enterprise.
						This is a Windows 10-only option, so other systems can be ignored safely.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Disable Windows Error Reporting" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Windows Error Reporting > Disable Windows Error Reporting.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so troubleshooting data - and possibly some file data - is sent to Windows. It is recommended to enable this so that this data is not sent.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, so no troubleshooting data is sent, which is the recommended option.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, so troubleshooting data - and possibly some file data - is sent to Windows. It is recommended to enable this so that this data is not sent.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Prevent installation of devices that match any of these device IDs" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > System > Device installation> Device Installation Restrictions > Prevent installation of devices that match these device IDs.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so a known hardware exploit to get to the stored data could possibly be used. It is recommended to enable this setting and follow the given guidelines.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, so assuming the guidance has been followed correctly, the known exploit will not work on Windows 8 and Server 2012. Make sure this does not affect any other existing hardware or software before rolling it out, and then ensure the next policy (which continues this) is correctly configured.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, so known hardware exploits to get to the stored data could possibly be used. It is recommended to enable this setting and follow the given guidelines.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Prevent installation of devices using drivers that match these device setup classes" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > System > Device installation> Device Installation Restrictions > Prevent installation of drivers matching these device setup classes.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so known hardware exploits to get to the stored data are possible to use. It is recommended to enable this setting and follow the given guidelines.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, so assuming the guidance has been followed properly, the known exploits should not work. Make sure this does not affect any other existing hardware or software before rolling it out.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, so known hardware exploits to get to the stored data are possible to use. It is recommended to enable this setting and follow the given guidelines.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Turn off Automatic Download and Install of updates" default="2" recommended="0">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Store > Turn off Automatic Download and Install of updates.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, which ensures updates are downloaded and installed automatically. This is the recommended setting.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, which means updates are not downloaded and installed automatically, which increases user burden and leaves more time before discovered exploits are patched for them to be used against the device. It is recommended to disable this.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured. By default, it will be disabled, and updates will happen automatically. 
						If you are not on Windows 10, this setting cannot be configured. However, this setting can be ignored. It is recommended to upgrade to the latest appropriate version of Windows.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Block launching Windows Store apps with Windows Runtime API access from hosted content." default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > App runtime > Block launching Windows Store apps with Windows Runtime API access from hosted content.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, which allows apps to be downloaded and run from the Windows Store, which could give a potential attacker a large amount of control over the device. It is recommended to enable this setting.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, limiting the control an attacker could potentially have from an app downloaded and run from the Windows Store.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured. By default, it will be disabled, which allows apps to be downloaded and run from the Windows Store, which could give a potential attacker a large amount of control over the device. It is recommended to enable this setting.
						If you do not have windows 10 you cannot and should not enable this policy and can safely ignore this.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Proxy definitions are authoritative" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Network > Network Isolation > Proxy definitions are authoritative.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, which allows users to use any Proxy. This is potentially less secure, and instead, it would be safer to disallow most proxies and only allow ones you know to be secure and necessary.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, limiting the proxies the user can use to the ones you allow. Ensure they are set up correctly - that any necessary proxies are allowed - and that this setting is tested properly before being fully rolled out.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured and, by default, disabled, which allows users to use any Proxy. This is potentially less secure, and instead, it would be safer to disallow most proxies and only allow ones you know to be secure and necessary.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Subnet definitions are authoritative" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Network > Network Isolation > Subnet definitions are authoritative.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, which allows users to use any subnet privately. This is potentially less secure, and instead, it would be safer to disallow most subnets and only allow ones you know to be secure and necessary.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, limiting the subnets the user can use privately to ones you allow. Ensure they are set up correctly - that any necessary subnets are allowed - and that this setting is tested properly before being fully rolled out.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured and, by default, disabled, which allows users to use any subnet privately. This is potentially less secure, and instead, it would be safer to disallow most subnets and only allow ones you know to be secure and necessary.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Windows To Go Default Startup Options" default="2" recommended="0">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Portable Operating System > Windows To Go Default Startup Options.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so Windows To Go cannot be used without the device user specifically allowing it. For this policy, this is the most secure option.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, allowing Windows To Go to be booted from a USB device. While device files should be hidden, some can be found quite easily, so it is safest to disable this policy.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured and, by default, will be unpredictable, as local administrators can activate or deactivate this on their devices, potentially allowing Windows To Go to be booted from a USB device. While device files should be hidden, some can be found quite easily, so it is safest to disable this policy.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Block Non-Admins from Safe Mode" default="0" recommended="0">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						There is one other policy, found under "Computer Configuration > Preferences > Windows Settings > Registry" and then Add a new item, action Replace, Hive: HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE, Key Path: SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\policies\system, Value name: SafeModeBlockNonAdmins, Value type: REG_DWORD, Value data: 1
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Summary" default="0" recommended="0" recommendedColour="Black">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						These policies will help to secure your network against more physical hardware threats. However, unlike some of the more purely beneficial policies, like lockout and password, these policies may not be viable due to specific hardware use.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
		</Policies>
	</Policy-Summary>
	<Policy-Summary number="5">
		<Header>
			Windows Defender configuration
		</Header>
		<Base-Text>
			If you use Windows Defender, the following policies are for configuring the included security features. If you do not use Windows Defender, these policies can be safely skipped.
		</Base-Text>
		<Vuln>
			Currently, there are vulnerabilities with your Windows Defender. Follow the guidance in the following pages to secure yourself against these vulnerabilities.
		</Vuln>
		<Not-Vuln>
			Currently, there are no detected vulnerabilities with your Windows Defender. The search is not guaranteed to be exhaustive, so some vulnerabilities may still exist, just not the most serious ones that are currently known. While it is recommended to look at the policies you have set to understand why they are important, you can skip this section below.
		</Not-Vuln>
		<Vulnerabilities>
			<Vulnerability position="1">
				Block, at first sight, is not enabled, so files will not be checked by Windows before being run. This also only works with the correct application of other policies in this section.
			</Vulnerability>
			<Vulnerability position="3">
				Your real-time protection is not configured well, and so it is possible, without specific user intervention, a malicious program, file, etc., will be downloaded and run.
			</Vulnerability>
		</Vulnerabilities>
		<Policies>
			<Policy name="Join Microsoft MAPS" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Windows Defender Antivirus > MAPS > Join Microsoft MAPS.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, which, if Windows Defender is not being used or if the operating system is below Windows 10, is fine. Otherwise, this setting should be enabled and set to either Basic or Advanced (depending on the needs of the network).
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Thus setting is enabled, which is the secure option if on Windows 10 and using Windows Defender, and not an issue otherwise.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, which, if Windows Defender is not being used or if the operating system is below Windows 10, is fine. Otherwise, this setting should be enabled and set to either Basic or Advanced (depending on the needs of the network).
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Configure the 'Block at First Sight' feature" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Windows Defender Antivirus > MAPS > Configure the 'Block at First Sight.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, which prevents Windows from screening files before allowing them to be run. It is much more secure to enable this and the other recommended policies in this section so that this policy can function.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Thus setting is enabled, which means if the other policies in this section are correctly implemented, Microsoft will check potentially harmful files when they are downloaded before they can be used and block any that are likely to be dangerous.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, which prevents Windows from screening files before allowing them to be run. It is much more secure to enable this and the other recommended policies in this section so that this policy can function.
						This policy is Windows 10 only and so cannot be set otherwise. This is an example of a security feature unavailable outside of Windows 10.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Send file samples when further analysis is required" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Windows Defender Antivirus > MAPS > Send file samples when further analysis is required.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, which prevents the previous policies from working. It is recommended to enable this and set it to 'Send safe samples automatically.'
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Thus setting is enabled, which should allow the previous policies to work, unless it has been set to 'Never send'. It is recommended to set it to 'Send safe samples automatically'.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, which prevents the previous policies from working. It is recommended to enable this and set it to 'Send safe samples automatically.'
						Unless you are not on Windows 10, in which case the previous policies cannot be set at all.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Turn off real-time protection" default="2" recommended="0">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Windows Defender Antivirus > Real-time Protection > Turn off real-time protection.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, which ensures Windows Defender can run properly and allows the 'Block at first sight' feature to work.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, which prevents Windows Defender from functioning fully, and turns off the 'Block at first sight' feature. It is strongly recommended to disable this policy.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, allowing users to enable it, which prevents Windows Defender from functioning fully, and would turn off the 'Block at first sight' feature. It is strongly recommended to disable this policy.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Configure Windows SmartScreen" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This policy can find this setting under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > File Explorer > Configure Windows SmartScreen.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so local administrators can configure Windows SmartScreen themselves, choosing to enable or disable it. If you want to control these configurations, you should enable this policy.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, meaning the Windows SmartScreen is unchangeable by local admins and base users. With this setting enabled, you can choose if SmartScreen is turned on or off for all users.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, so local administrators can configure Windows SmartScreen themselves, choosing to enable or disable it. If you want to control these configurations, you should enable this policy.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
		</Policies>
	</Policy-Summary>
	<Policy-Summary number="5">
		<Header>
			AppLocker configuration
		</Header>
		<Base-Text>
			AppLocker is a built-in tool that allows you to block certain applications, files, and scripts on all devices. Alternatively, you can disable all by default and only allow certain applications you know you need.
		</Base-Text>
		<Vuln></Vuln>
		<Not-Vuln></Not-Vuln>
		<Vulnerabilities>
			<Vulnerability position="1"></Vulnerability>
		</Vulnerabilities>
		<Policies>
			<Policy name="Executable Rules" default="0" recommended="1" nonRecommendedColour="Orange">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Exceptions are added by right-clicking on the rule, clicking properties, going to the exceptions tab, and setting the dropdown to the bracketed option.
						First, generate the default rules so system files can run normally.
						Allow Everyone: All files located in the Windows Defender\Platform folder -
						%OSDrive%\ProgramData\Microsoft\Windows Defender\Platform\*
						Allow Everyone: All files located in the Program Files folder - with exceptions
						Exception: (Path) %PROGRAMFILES%\Windows Kits\*\Debuggers\*
						Allow Everyone: All files located in the Windows folder - with exceptions
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\com\dmp\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\FxsTmp\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Spool\drivers\color\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Spool\PRINTERS\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Spool\SERVERS\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Tasks\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\microsoft\crypto\rsa\machinekeys\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\tasks\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\temp\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\tracing\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\registration\crmlog\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\servicing\packages\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\servicing\sessions\*
						Exception: (Publisher) %SYSTEM32%\WMIC.exe,*
						Exception: (Publisher) %SYSTEM32%\cmstp.exe,*
						Exception: (Publisher) %SYSTEM32%\mshta.exe,*
						Exception: (Publisher) %SYSTEM32%\PresentationHost.exe,*
						Exception: (Publisher) %SYSTEM32%\windbg.exe,*
						Exception: (Publisher) %SYSTEM32%\cipher.exe,*
						Exception: (Publisher) %Microsoft.NET%\Framework64\*\IEExec.exe
						Exception: (Publisher) %Microsoft.NET%\Framework64\*\InstallUtil.exe
						Exception: (Publisher) %Microsoft.NET%\Framework\*\regsvcs.exe
						Exception: (Publisher) %Microsoft.NET%\Framework\*\msbuild.exe
						Exception: (Publisher) %Microsoft.NET%\Framework\*\regasm.exe
						Allow Administrators: All files
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1"></Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Windows Installer Rules" default="0" recommended="0" recommendedColour="Orange">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Exceptions are added by right-clicking on the rule, clicking properties, going to the exceptions tab, and setting the dropdown to the bracketed option.
						First, generate the default rules so system files can run normally.
						Allow Administrators: All Windows Installer files
						Allow Everyone: %WINDIR%\Installer\*
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Script Rules" default="0" recommended="0" recommendedColour="Orange">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Exceptions are added by right-clicking on the rule, clicking properties, going to the exceptions tab, and setting the dropdown to the bracketed option.
						First, generate the default rules so system files can run normally.
						Allow Everyone: All Scripts located in the Program Files folder
						Allow Everyone: All Scripts located in the Windows folder - with exceptions
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\com\dmp\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\FxsTmp\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Spool\drivers\color\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Spool\PRINTERS\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Spool\SERVERS\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Tasks\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\registration\crmlog\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\tasks\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\temp\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\tracing\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\servicing\packages\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\servicing\sessions\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\microsoft\crypto\rsa\machinekeys\*
						Allow Administrators: All scripts
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Packaged app Rules" default="0" recommended="0" recommendedColour="Orange">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Exceptions are added by right-clicking on the rule, clicking properties, going to the exceptions tab, and setting the dropdown to the bracketed option.
						First, generate the default rules so system files can run normally.
						Allow Everyone: All signed packaged apps
						Exception: (Publisher) Microsoft.Get started
						Exception: (Publisher) Microsoft.MicrosoftOfficeHub
						Exception: (Publisher) Microsoft.SkypeApp
						Exception: (Publisher) Microsoft.WindowsFeedback
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="DLL Rules" default="0" recommended="0" recommendedColour="Orange">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Exceptions are added by right-clicking on the rule, clicking properties, going to the exceptions tab, and setting the dropdown to the bracketed option.
						First, generate the default rules so system files can run normally.
						Allow Everyone: All DLLs located in the Windows Defender\Platform folder -
						%OSDrive%\ProgramData\Microsoft\Windows Defender\Platform\*
						Allow Everyone: All DLLs located in the Program Files folder
						Allow Everyone: All DLLs located in the Windows folder - with exceptions
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\com\dmp\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\FxsTmp\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Spool\drivers\color\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Spool\PRINTERS\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Spool\SERVERS\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\Tasks\*
						Exception: (Path) %SYSTEM32%\microsoft\crypto\rsa\machinekeys\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\registration\crmlog\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\tasks\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\temp\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\tracing\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\servicing\packages\*
						Exception: (Path) %WINDIR%\servicing\sessions\*
						Allow Administrators: All DLLs
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
		</Policies>
	</Policy-Summary>
	<Policy-Summary number="7">
		<Header>
			BitLocker Configuration
		</Header>
		<Base-Text>
			BitLocker is a built-in encryption tool that encrypts the storage of devices when not in use. If a device is stolen, lost, or decommissioned inappropriately, an attacker could access the (potentially sensitive) data with no authorization - for example, by simply moving the hard drive to another computer.
		</Base-Text>
		<Vuln></Vuln>
		<Not-Vuln></Not-Vuln>
		<Vulnerabilities>
			<Vulnerability position="1"></Vulnerability>
		</Vulnerabilities>
		<Policies>
			<Policy name="Enforce drive encryption type on operating system drives" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This policy can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > BitLocker Drive Encryption > Operating System Drives > Enforce drive encryption type on operating system drives.
					This setting determines how BitLocker will encrypt the data or allows the user to choose. The choices are either Full Encryption (all data) or Used Space Only encryption (only encrypts data in use).
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled so that users can choose their encryption settings. BitLocker will encrypt any operational data, but if the user decides to use the faster 'Used Space Only encryption,' then any data that BitLocker wiped from the device before the user started using it will be left in unused storage unencrypted. The recommended action is to enable this policy and choose 'Full Encryption.'
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled will give you three options: the default - which allows the user to choose the same as disabling; used Space Only encryption - which can leave some previously deleted files available to recover unencrypted, or Full Encryption, which encrypts all data, even if it is not in use. In general, Full Encryption is recommended.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured so that users can choose their encryption settings. BitLocker will encrypt any operational data, but if the user decides to use the faster 'Used Space Only encryption,' any data that BitLocker wiped from the device before the user started using it will be left unused storage unencrypted. The recommended action is to enable this policy and choose 'Full Encryption.'
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Require additional authentication at startup" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > BitLocker Drive Encryption > Operating System Drives > Require additional authentication at startup.
					This setting gives extra options to configure BitLocker securely. This offers different options for authentication when turning on the device.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, making BitLocker much easier to decrypt, especially with a user's normal login credentials. By enabling this, you can force users to create their BitLocker more securely, protecting their data further.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, giving you various options to make a user's BitLocker more secure. Even with this configured, it is best to review the choices you have set. Check guidance for a more in-depth evaluation of this policy.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, making BitLocker much easier to decrypt, especially with a user's normal login credentials. By enabling this, you can force users to make their BitLocker more secure, protecting their data further.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="PIN configuration" default="0" recommended="0" recommendedColour="Black">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						If PINs are required (which they should be), then the following settings will allow you to configure how BitLocker can set the PINs, similar to password settings (though less extensive). These should be set to ensure PINs are more secure and harder to brute force.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Allow enhanced PINs for startup" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > BitLocker Drive Encryption > Operating System Drives > Allow enhanced PINs for a startup.
					This policy is similar to password complexity because it allows upper case, lower case, numbers, and special characters.
					However, this policy only allows them instead of requiring them and disabling all characters except numerals.
					Because of this, there is no reason to leave this unconfigured or disable it, as that is not allowing users to be more secure.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so PINs have to be numerical. These are easier to crack than more complex PINs, so this setting should allow the user to have more complex PINs.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting enables users to make complex PINs that are harder to crack. However, this does not force them; they can still use numerical PINs. So this is the more secure option without compromising user experience.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, so PINs have to be numerical. These are easier to crack than more complex PINs, so this setting should allow the user to have more complex PINs.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Configure minimum PIN length for startup" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > BitLocker Drive Encryption > Operating System Drives > Configure minimum PIN length for the startup.
					This policy is similar to the minimum password length for fairly obvious reasons.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled so that PINs can be of any length between 4 and 20. Realistically this is not massively insecure as BitLocker only allows a limited number of attempts, making even a four-digit password unlikely to be cracked; however, longer PINs will reduce the chances further, for example, in the case where multiple devices are lost/stolen.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting enables you to set a minimum PIN length for all users. A value for this cannot easily be recommended, as it depends on the importance of the data, the storage of recovery PINs, and other security measures.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured so that PINs can be of any length between 4 and 20. Realistically this is not massively insecure as BitLocker only allows a limited number of attempts, making even a four-digit password unlikely to be cracked; however, longer PINs will reduce the chances further, for example, in the case where multiple devices are lost/stolen.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Configure use of passwords for operating system drives" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > BitLocker Drive Encryption > Operating System Drives > Configure the use of passwords for operating system drives.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, allowing basic passwords to be used so hackers can crack them more easily. These passwords should not be used if a TPM is installed, so that this policy may be irrelevant. If these passwords are likely to be used, TPM should be enabled in this policy, and the guidance followed.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting allows you to set requirements for passwords that will be used without a TPM. Ensure you configure the options according to the guidance.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, allowing basic passwords to be used that can be cracked more easily. These passwords should not be used if a TPM is installed so that this policy may be irrelevant. If these passwords are likely to be used, this policy should be enabled, and the guidance followed.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Summary" default="0" recommended="0" recommendedColour="Black">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Without setting up BitLocker, if a device is lost, an attacker breaks into an office and copies the contents of a hard drive, or if a device is decommissioned without properly wiping data, it is quite easy to recover any amount of sensitive data from it.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
		</Policies>
	</Policy-Summary>
	<Policy-Summary number="2">
		<Header>
			Windows Defender Exploit Guard configuration
		</Header>
		<Base-Text>
			Windows Defender Exploit Guard is another built-in security tool you can configure and use. There are four features advertised as part of Exploit Guard, and all but the first require Windows Defender Antivirus:
			Exploit protection - works with antivirus software to apply to exploit mitigation to the apps your users use.
			Attack surface reduction rules - use intelligent rules to help stop Office, script, and email-based exploits.
		</Base-Text>
		<Vuln></Vuln>
		<Not-Vuln></Not-Vuln>
		<Vulnerabilities>
			<Vulnerability position="1"></Vulnerability>
		</Vulnerabilities>
		<Policies>
			<Policy name="Controlled folder access" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Windows Defender Antivirus > Windows Defender Exploit Guard > Controlled folder access.
					This setting determines what folders can be accessed by files that have been determined malicious or suspicious.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so any malicious files discovered by Windows are only blocked from accessing protected Windows system files means they can still access most, if not all, personal and company (including sensitive) files. This setting is strongly recommended to be enabled and the mode set to Block.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, allowing you control over what files can be accessed by files that have been determined malicious or suspicious. It is strongly recommended to ensure this policy Mode is set to Block so that these files cannot access personal and other sensitive files.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, so any malicious files discovered by Windows are only blocked from accessing protected Windows system files. This means they can still access most, if not all, personal and company (including sensitive) files. This setting is strongly recommended to be enabled and the mode set to Block.
						As with the remainder of Windows Defender Exploit Guard, this is Windows 10 only and can be ignored otherwise. It is still strongly recommended to update to the latest version of Windows.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Use a common set of exploit protection settings" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > Windows Components > Windows Defender Exploit Guard > Use a common set of exploit protection settings.
					This setting is simply for importing the settings configured elsewhere (Windows Defender Security Center application or exported from EMET) as an XML file and then uploaded here.
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so to upload an XML with the configuration, this setting must first be enabled.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled so that you can upload an XML with the configuration using this setting.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, so to upload an XML with the configuration, this setting must first be enabled.
						If you are not on Windows 10, this setting cannot be configured with the entirety of Windows Defender Exploit Guard. It is still strongly recommended to update to the latest version of Windows.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
		</Policies>
	</Policy-Summary>
	<Policy-Summary number="1">
		<Header>
			Windows Defender Device Guard configuration
		</Header>
		<Base-Text>
			Windows Defender Device Guard is another tool Windows supplies which includes Windows Defender Application Control (WDAC), allowing admins to restrict user devices to only running digitally signed applications.
			Administrators can choose to allow certain unsigned but trusted applications. However, these apply to all users, including administrators, so for split privileges, this should be used in conjunction with AppLocker.
			The Microsoft website provides guidance on how to create a WDAC policy and deploy it. Before fully rolling it out to all users, this should be thoroughly tested, guidance for which can also be found on the Microsoft website.

			Do note that this entire policy is Windows 10 only. AppLocker can generally be used as an alternative, though it may only be as effective or reliable in some cases.
			This is a particular instance in which not having an upgrade to Windows 10 causes security vulnerabilities, and the number will continue to grow as more fall out of support.
		</Base-Text>
		<Vuln></Vuln>
		<Not-Vuln></Not-Vuln>
		<Vulnerabilities>
			<Vulnerability position="1"></Vulnerability>
		</Vulnerabilities>
		<Policies>
			<Policy name="Turn On Virtualization Based Security" default="2" recommended="1">
				<Guidance>
					Virtualization-based security is located at "Computer Configuration > Policies > Administrative Templates > System > Device Guard > Turn On Virtualisation Based Security."
					This setting helps to guard against malicious software being loaded into the Windows kernel. This setting should be enabled, and the following options should be set:
					Platform Security should be set to Secure Boot and DMA Protection
					Virtualization Based Protection of Code Integrity should be set to Enabled with UEFI Lock
					Require UEFI Memory Attributes Table should be set to True (However, this can only be set with UEFI 2.6+)
					Credential Guard Configuration should be set to Enabled with UEFI Lock
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						This setting is disabled, so the Windows kernel is vulnerable to malicious software being downloaded. This setting should be enabled, and the options set as given in the guidance.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						This setting is enabled, so to protect the Windows kernel against malicious software, follow the options in the guidance.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						This setting is not configured, so the Windows kernel is vulnerable to malicious software being downloaded. This setting should be enabled, and the options set as given in the guidance.
						If you are not on Windows 10, this setting cannot be configured with the entirety of Windows Defender Device Guard. It is still strongly recommended to update to the latest version of Windows.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
		</Policies>
	</Policy-Summary>
	<Policy-Summary number="7">
		<Header>
			Windows Defender Firewall configuration
		</Header>
		<Base-Text>
			The built-in Windows Defender Firewall is a powerful tool to defend against threats and always-on-VPN configuration.
			The following configuration will:
			Force the firewall to be enabled on all devices, on Domain, Private, and Public networks.
			Block all Inbound connections that were not initiated by the device.
			Block all outbound connections when connected to a public or private network, with some exceptions for basic functionality.
			Allow all outbound connections when connected to the domain network.
			Configure an always-on VPN.
		</Base-Text>
		<Vuln></Vuln>
		<Not-Vuln></Not-Vuln>
		<Vulnerabilities>
			<Vulnerability position="1"></Vulnerability>
		</Vulnerabilities>
		<Policies>
			<Policy name="Domain Profile" default="2" recommended="1" >
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under "Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Windows Firewall with Advanced Security."
					In the overview tab, you must configure the firewall as these states:
					For domain and private connection: allow both inbound and outbound
					For public connection: Only allow outbound; inbound is blocked
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Windows Firewall is disabled on Domain Networks. This means if an attacker is on your network, Windows Firewall is completely disallowed from giving any protection. This should be enabled to allow Windows Firewall to protect your devices and the guidance followed.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Windows Firewall is enabled on Domain Networks. This means users cannot disable the firewall, which is active against threats. Follow the guidance to ensure it defends effectively and that users cannot change any internal options.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						Windows Firewall is not configured on Domain Networks. This means that if an attacker is on your network, the ability of Windows Firewall to protect your devices completely depends upon users choosing the correct policies. To allow Windows Firewall to protect your devices more comprehensively, this should be enabled - removing the responsibility from users - and the guidelines followed.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Domain Profile - Apply local firewall rules" default="2" recommended="0">
				<Guidance>
					Firewall Policies locate in "Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Windows Firewall with Advanced Security."
					In the overview tab, select Windows Firewall Properties, and go to the Private Profile tab. Then click on Customize in Settings.
					In Customize Settings, go to Rule merging, and set the "Apply local firewall" to "No." This policy prevents local Administrators from overriding these Firewall policies and connecting insecurely to the public network
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Apply local firewall rules is set to No on Domain Networks. This means local administrators cannot override the (hopefully) secure firewall policies to open up security holes in your network.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Apply local firewall rules is set to Yes on Domain Networks. This means local administrators can override the firewall policies and open up security vulnerabilities. To disallow this, this setting should be set to No. The location can be found in the guidance.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						Apply local firewall rules is set to Not configured and by default Yes on Domain Networks. This means local administrators can override the firewall policies and open up security vulnerabilities. To disallow this, this setting should be set to No. The location can be found in the guidance.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Private Profile" default="2" recommended="0">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under "Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Windows Firewall with Advanced Security."
					In the overview tab, you must configure the firewall as these states:
					For domain and private connection: allow both inbound and outbound
					For public connection: Only allow outbound; inbound is blocked
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Windows Firewall is disabled on Private Networks. If a user removes a device (such as a laptop) from the workplace and connects to a private network, Windows Firewall cannot defend against any security threats that may be on that network. This should be enabled to allow Windows Firewall to protect your devices and the guidance followed.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Windows Firewall is enabled on Private Networks. This means users cannot disable the firewall, which is active against threats. Follow the guidance to ensure it defends effectively and that users cannot change any internal options.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						Windows Firewall is not configured on Private Networks. If a user removes a device (such as a laptop) from the workplace and connects to a private network, Windows Firewall cannot defend against any security threats that may be on that network unless the user has set/left the correct policies. This should be enabled to allow Windows Firewall to protect your devices without the risk otherwise, and the guidance followed.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Private Profile - Apply local firewall rules" default="2" recommended="0">
				<Guidance>
					Firewall Policies locate in "Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Windows Firewall with Advanced Security."
					In the overview tab, select Windows Firewall Properties, and go to the Private Profile tab. Then click on Customize in Settings.
					In Customize Settings, go to Rule merging, and set the "Apply local firewall" to "No." This policy prevents local Administrators from overriding these Firewall policies and connecting insecurely to the public network
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Apply local firewall rules is set to No on Private Networks. This means local administrators cannot override the (hopefully) secure firewall policies to open up security holes in their devices when on another private network.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Apply local firewall rules is set to Yes on Private Networks. This means local administrators can override the firewall policies and open security vulnerabilities. To disallow this, this setting should be set to No. The location can be found in the guidance.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						Apply local firewall rules is set to Not configured and by default Yes on Private Networks. This means local administrators can override the firewall policies and open security vulnerabilities. To disallow this, this setting should be set to No. The location can be found in the guidance.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Public Profile" default="2" recommended="0">
				<Guidance>
					This setting can be found under "Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Windows Firewall with Advanced Security."
					In the overview tab, you must configure the firewall as these states:
					For domain and private connection: allow both inbound and outbound
					For public connection: Only allow outbound; inbound is blocked
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Windows Firewall is disabled on Public Networks. If a user removes a device (such as a laptop) from the workplace and connects to a public network, Windows Firewall cannot defend against any security threats from anyone who connects to this network, including any potential attacker. This should be enabled to allow Windows Firewall to protect your devices and the guidance followed.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Windows Firewall is enabled on Public Networks. This means users cannot disable the firewall, which is active against threats. Follow the guidance to ensure it defends effectively and that users cannot change any internal options.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						Windows Firewall is not configured on Public Networks. Suppose a user removes a device (such as a laptop) from the workplace and connects to a public network. In that case, Windows Firewall cannot defend against any security threats from anyone who connects to this network, including any potential attacker, without the user choosing/allowing the correct policies. To remove this responsibility from users, this should be enabled, and the guidance followed.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Public Profile - Apply local firewall rules" default="2" recommended="0">
				<Guidance>
					Firewall Policies locate in "Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Windows Firewall with Advanced Security."
					In the overview tab, select Windows Firewall Properties, and go to the Public Profile tab. Then click on Customize in Settings.
					In Customize Settings, go to Rule merging, and set the "Apply local firewall" to "No." This policy prevents local Administrators from overriding these Firewall policies and connecting insecurely to the public network
				</Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Apply local firewall rules is set to No on Public Networks. This means local administrators cannot override the (hopefully) secure firewall policies to open up security holes in their devices when on a public network.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1">
						Apply local firewall rules is set to Yes on Public Networks. This means local administrators can override the firewall policies and open security vulnerabilities. To disallow this, this setting should be set to No. The location can be found in the guidance.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="2-2">
						Apply local firewall rules is set to Not configured and by default Yes on Public Networks. This means local administrators can override the firewall policies and open security vulnerabilities. To disallow this, this setting should be set to No. The location can be found in the guidance.
					</Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
			<Policy name="Outbound rules" default="0" recommended="1" nonRecommendedColour="Orange">
				<Guidance></Guidance>
				<Advice>
					<Threshold threshold="0-0">
						Outlined here are instructions to set up outbound rules that allow users to use private and public networks to some limited degree while compromising security as little as possible. You can configure the firewall in "Computer Configuration > Policies > Windows Settings > Security Settings > Windows Firewall with Advanced Security."

						Rule: Allow outbound DHCP for clients to obtain IP Addresses.
						Allow port 67 and port 68 locally (on both UDP and TCP) while leaving everything else as default, or you can use DHCP Predefined configurations.

						Rule: Allow outbound DNS for clients to resolve DNS queries.
						Allow port 53 locally on UDP and TCP while leaving everything else as default, or you can use DNS Predefined configurations.

						Rule: Allow outbound Kerberos to ensure authentication to connect to the internet is properly.
						To enable this, ensure all your Windows clients are compatible with Kerberos. By default, Windows will automatically enable this feature.

						Rule: Allow outbound LDAP.
						Allow port 389 locally on UDP and TCP while leaving everything else as default, or you can use LDAP/Active Directory Domain Services Predefined configurations.

						Rule: Allow outbound NCSI probe.
						To enable this, ensure all your Windows clients are compatible with this feature. By default, Windows will automatically enable this feature.
					</Threshold>
					<Threshold threshold="1-1"></Threshold>
				</Advice>
			</Policy>
		</Policies>
	</Policy-Summary>
</Policies>